# AJAY PREETI SIDHARTH () Featured

Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Engineering, Project Management, Change Management, Incident Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, Production Support, Application Support, Manual Testing, Eclipse IDE, Putty, Unix, JIRA, HTML, Java, SQL.



Current Designation: Software Engineer Total Experience: 3 Year(s) 6 Month(s)

Current Company: HCL Technologies Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Noida Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Hyderabad, Bengaluru / Bangalore, Delhi / NCR Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Engineer/Developer, Software Engineering, Project Management, Change Management, Incident Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, Production Support, Application Support, Manual

Testing, Eclipse IDE, Putty, Unix, JIRA, HTML, Java, SQL, Linux

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

### Summary

A value driven and highly competent Software Engineer at HCL Tech with 3+ years of experience in Application Support and Production Support. Good knowledge of Healthcare and Pharmaceutical domain and Automobile domain. Having strong technical acumen with analytical skills, demonstrated ability to manage multiple priorities and developing solutions in a rapidly changing environment. Extensive knowledge in Production Support (L2 /L3 Level of Support). Hands-on in SQL Query, Oracle Database and Java technology and willing to work as a key player in challenging & creative environment. Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Engineering, Project Management, Change Management, Incident Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, Production Support, Application Support, Manual Testing, Eclipse IDE, Putty, Unix/Linux, JIRA, HTML, Java, SQL Query.

# Work Experience

**HCL Technologies** as Software Engineer Jul 2017 to Till Date

Software Engineer looking for roles in Production support and Application Support. Experience of 3 years for developing and supporing application. Good knowledge of Health care and Pharmaceutical. Having strong technical acumen with analytical skills, demonstrated ability to manage multiple priorities and developing solutions in a rapidly changing environment. Extensive knowledge in Production Support (L2 /L3 Level of Support). Hands-on in Java technology and Databases and willing to work as a key player in challenging & creative environment.

Project Line of business Technical Environment Type of Assignment Role Merck AMS Consolidation MRL Healthcare Java and Oracle Software Development and Production Support Software Developer & Analyser

Description: Merck is an American multinational pharmaceutical company and one of the largest pharmaceutical companies in the world. It operates as Merck & Co. in North America, the original Merck based in Darmstadt. It has major research and development centres. AMS Merck Research Laboratory Clinical Division which support several user applications like IDP CRF Submit Central Designer, DSA and Pinnacle 21. Work over the incidents, Change Management, PBI and work order of client issues, application development and enhancement.

- ? Develop and Analyse the code for system Testing and debugging.
- ? Work on enhancement and upgrade of application by using Java and SQL.
- ? Support GXP applications using Java and SQL.
- ? Debugging the application for errors faced by end users/client and giving them definitive solution during UAT, Production
- & Post Production support along with the parameterization of the product.
- ? Work on Incident, Problem & Change Management (IT Service Management Processes).

- ? Handle scheduled task scripts and gueries within an agreed time frame.
- ? Follow up and Co-ordination with different teams to resolve any issue.
- ? Worked as responsible resource for sharing domain and database objects/tables used in the project and helped other team members in development and execution of different SQL scripts.
- ? Monitored and optimized performance, resources, availability, and operation of all systems
- ? Documented and complied with company policies and standard operating procedures.
- ? Batch Monitoring / Business Process Monitoring in large application setups.
- ? Maintain SLAs in 24\*7 operations mode.
- ? Log Analysis & Trouble Shooting of Complex Issues.
- ? Good knowledge of Oracle Database & SQL Queries.
- ? Basics of OS & Windows Task Scheduler.
- ? Global Client Communication; Managing multiple stakeholders.

Project Line of business Technical Environment Type of Assignment Role TRW Automotive Automobiles Java and Unix Software Development and Production Support Software Developer, Designer & Analyzer

Description: TRW Automotive is an American global supplier of automotive systems, modules, and components to automotive original equipment manufacturers and related aftermarkets. Its headquartered in Livonia, Michigan, United States. Work performed on QAD Supplier Portal, Sonic Middleware and Service desk. Client issue reported over the incidents, Change Management, PBI and work order.

Duration: July 2017 to May 2018.

Responsibilities

- ? Develop, Analyze and test the module of the application.
- ? Work on enhancement and upgrade of application by using Java and SQL.
- ? Responsible for support, maintenance and implementation of small to medium non-complex components of a project
- ? Supporting and maintaining application like QAD Supplier Portal, Sonic Middleware and Service desk.
- ? Work on Incident, Problem & Change Management
- ? Good knowledge of Java Technology.
- ? Global Client Communication; Managing multiple stakeholders.

### **Education**

UG: BCA (Computers) from SHREE NARAYAN SINGH COLLEGE MOTIHARI in 2013

PG: MCA (Computers) from Vellore Institute of Technology in 2016

#### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
ALM,Hp Alm	
Unix	
GXP application	
Linux	
IQ OQ	
JAVA	
ORACLE DBA	
SQL	
SQL Database	
Oracle Database	

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				

Hindi

# **Projects**

Project Title: Merck AMS Consolidation

Client: Merck

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: May 2018 - Dec 2020

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Merck is an American multinational pharmaceutical company and one of the largest pharmaceutical companies in the world. It operates as Merck & Co. in North America, the original Merck based in Darmstadt. It has major research and development centers. Basically work was to enhance the performance and design a new code to give customer satisfaction in Java and Oracle Technology.

Project Title: TRW Automotive Automobiles

Client: TRW AUTOMOTIVE Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Jul 2017 - May 2018 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: TRW Automotive is an American global supplier of automotive systems, modules, and components to automotive original equipment manufacturers and related aftermarkets. Basically work was to enhance the performance and design a new code to give best customer satisfaction in Java and Oracle Technology.

### **Affirmative Action**

### **Work Authorization**

Category: General

Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time